<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>play-framework on Petros Papapanagiotou</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/techs/play-framework/</link><description>Recent content in play-framework on Petros Papapanagiotou</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© Petros Papapanagiotou</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:56:14 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.petrospap.com/techs/play-framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Logic-based workflows</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 23:28:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</guid><description>This project aims to enhance the development of process workflows with AI techniques so that various properties of the models are verified as they are being built, i.e. workflows that are correct-by-construction.
In particular, we employ the proofs-as-processes paradigm which describes the correspondence between Classical Linear Logic (CLL) proofs with π-calculus processes. This enables us to create resource-based specifications of processes as logical sequents and compose them via formal proof. The result is a verified workflow with the following properties:</description></item><item><title>DigiFlow</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/digiflow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:56:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/digiflow/</guid><description>Digitizing Industrial Workflow, Monitoring and Optimization Digiflow is an Industry 4.0 project funded by EIT Digital. It focuses on the digitization, monitoring, and optimization of industrial workflows, with a combination of IoT sensors, Cloud infrastructure and our workflow technologies.
A slide deck with some of the aspects and outputs of the project for 2018 can be found HERE
We are working on a unique solution to enable manufacturing companies to better monitor their floors and provide decision support towards efficiency optimisation:</description></item></channel></rss>