<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Petros Papapanagiotou</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/</link><description>Recent content on Petros Papapanagiotou</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© Petros Papapanagiotou</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 21:23:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.petrospap.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SuprNation</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/suprnation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 23:02:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/suprnation/</guid><description>SuprNation is a technology company founded in 2015 to serve as a home for some of the most competent and creative people in the iGaming industry. Our first product was launched in the summer of 2016, a casino determined to deliver a better user and gaming experience than what is currently available. SuprNation is a highly ambitious project with 3 casino brands, VoodooDreams, NYSpins and Duelz live on the market.</description></item><item><title>Logic-based workflows</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 23:28:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</guid><description>This project aims to enhance the development of process workflows with AI techniques so that various properties of the models are verified as they are being built, i.e. workflows that are correct-by-construction.
In particular, we employ the proofs-as-processes paradigm which describes the correspondence between Classical Linear Logic (CLL) proofs with π-calculus processes. This enables us to create resource-based specifications of processes as logical sequents and compose them via formal proof. The result is a verified workflow with the following properties:</description></item><item><title>Cats-Actors</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/cats-actors/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:22:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/cats-actors/</guid><description>Cats-Actors 🐱 is a functional programming-based actor system derived from Akka Akka v2.6.21.
It is available under the Apache 2.0 License on GitHub: https://github.com/suprnation/cats-actors
Description The following text taken from the project README (original author: Mark Galea) introduces Cats-Actors, its main goal and benefits.
Introduction Actors are the fundamental units of computation in the Actor Model, encapsulating state and behavior. They interact exclusively through asynchronous message passing, ensuring their state is accessed sequentially.</description></item><item><title>Proter</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/proter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:22:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/proter/</guid><description>Proter is an open-source discrete event simulation library for workflows, written in Scala. It is part of our WorkflowFM framework for formal workflow modelling and management.
It is available under the Apache 2.0 License on GitHub: https://github.com/workflowfm/proter
Website and documentation is available here: http://docs.workflowfm.com/proter/
Proter was initially developed for the simulation of logic-based workflows in WorkflowFM in the context of the DigiFlow project. It was then gradually sepHarated into an independent project for general purpose process simulation.</description></item><item><title>WorkflowFM Reasoner</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/reasoner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:32:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/reasoner/</guid><description>The WorkflowFM Reasoner is a logic-based library for correct-by-construction process modelling and composition.
It is available under the Apache 2.0 License on GitHub: https://github.com/workflowfm/workflowfm-reasoner
Website and documentation is available here: http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-reasoner/
About It is implemented as a logic-based library for the interactive theorem prover HOL Light that allows for rigorous, formally verified process specification and composition. The resulting workflows are correct-by-construction with the following verified properties:
Systematic resource accounting: No resources appear out of nowhere or disappear into thin air.</description></item><item><title>Business Process Simulation</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 23:07:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proter/</guid><description>Proter is an open-source discrete event simulation library for workflows, written in Scala. It is part of our WorkflowFM framework for formal workflow modelling and management and is available on GitHub:
https://github.com/workflowfm/proter
Website and documentation is available here: http://docs.workflowfm.com/proter/
Proter was initially developed for the simulation of logic-based workflows in WorkflowFM in the context of the DigiFlow project. It was then gradually separated into an independent project for general purpose process simulation.</description></item><item><title>PEW</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/pew/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:22:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/pew/</guid><description>PEW is a persistent execution engine for π-calculus workflows generated by the WorkflowFM process composition tools, written in Scala. It is part of our WorkflowFM framework for formal workflow modelling and management.
It is available under the Apache 2.0 License on GitHub: https://github.com/workflowfm/pew
Website and documentation is available here: http://docs.workflowfm.com/pew/</description></item><item><title>WorkflowFM Composer</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/composer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:32:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/composer/</guid><description>The WorkflowFM Composer is a a diagrammatic tool for formally verified process modelling and composition.
It is available under the Apache 2.0 License on GitHub: https://github.com/workflowfm/workflowfm-composer
Website and documentation is available here: http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/
About The WorkflowFM Composer consists of a Java-based server and GUI for formally verified process composition using the WorkflowFM Reasoner. It provides a visual, diagrammatic interface to specify processes based on their input and output resources, and compose them together to form more complex workflows.</description></item><item><title>HOL Light Embed</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/embedded-logics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:22:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/embedded-logics/</guid><description>I have developed a generic framework to perform object level reasoning with embedded logics in HOL Light. It provides procedural tactics inspired by Isabelle&amp;rsquo;s rule/erule/drule/frule. It also supports correspondences with computational terms in the style of Curry-Howard.
It is available under the BSD-3-Clause License on GitHub: https://github.com/PetrosPapapa/hol-light-embed
Additional information is available in this publication.
A step-by-step tutorial with a detailed example is available here.
What this library does Assuming you have an inductively defined logic encoded in HOL, the library allows you to prove object level theorems within your embedded logic.</description></item><item><title>Isabelle Light</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/isabelle-light/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:22:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/isabelle-light/</guid><description>HOL Light is a modern theorem proving system characterised by its powerful, low level interface that allows for flexibility and programmability. However, considerable effort is required to become accustomed to the system and to reach a point where one can comfortably achieve simple natural deduction proofs.
Isabelle is another powerful and widely used theorem prover that provides useful features for natural deduction proofs, including its meta-logic and its four main natural deduction tactics.</description></item><item><title>Boyer-Moore</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/boyer-moore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:22:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/boyer-moore/</guid><description>In this project, we investigate the potential of the Boyer-Moore waterfall model for the automation of inductive proofs within a modern proof assistant. Based on the concepts and methodology underlying this 40-year-old model, we have implemented a new, fully integrated tool in the theorem prover HOL Light that can be invoked as a tactic.
We have also included several extensions and enhancements to the model. These include the integration of existing HOL Light proof procedures and the addition of state-of-the-art generalization techniques into the waterfall.</description></item><item><title>HOL Light Tools</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/hol-light-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:22:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/hol-light-tools/</guid><description>This is a library of tools, tactics, and theories I have developed in HOL Light.
Some of these, such as the finite map theory, have been ported from the work of others, particularly in HOL4.
Notable things included:
A port of the finite map theory from HOL4. A set of tools to enable proofs in an arbitrarily extended proof state. A small library about substitution. Additional definitions and lemmas for lists, sets, multisets, etc.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Care Research Centre</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/acrc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 02:29:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/acrc/</guid><description>The Advanced Care Research Centre Programme is a complementary programme of research and development to deliver innovation and change to later life care. It has the following vision:
High‐quality data‐driven, personalised and affordable care that supports the independence, dignity and quality‐of‐life of people in later life living in their own homes and in supported care environments.
It is a large, multidisciplinary programme, involving 6 themes of core work and a doctoral Academy, and funded by Legal &amp;amp; General.</description></item><item><title>Explainable Maintenance Support</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/hitachi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:56:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/hitachi/</guid><description>In this project, I offered consultancy services to the Lumada Data Science Lab of Hitachi in Japan. The project focused on the exploration of Explainable AI solutions for maintenance support, drawing from actual IoT data from Hitachi manufacturing sites.
Maintenance operations in large manufacturing machines are complex and require expert knowledge and experience. The goal of the project was to explore novel AI solutions that incorporate IoT data, knowledge and domain expertise.</description></item><item><title>DigiFlow</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/digiflow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:56:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/digiflow/</guid><description>Digitizing Industrial Workflow, Monitoring and Optimization Digiflow is an Industry 4.0 project funded by EIT Digital. It focuses on the digitization, monitoring, and optimization of industrial workflows, with a combination of IoT sensors, Cloud infrastructure and our workflow technologies.
A slide deck with some of the aspects and outputs of the project for 2018 can be found HERE
We are working on a unique solution to enable manufacturing companies to better monitor their floors and provide decision support towards efficiency optimisation:</description></item><item><title>SOCIAM</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/sociam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:57:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/sociam/</guid><description>SOCIAM was an EPSRC funded project involving the Universities of Oxford, Edinburgh and Southampton, focusing on the theory and practice of social machines.
The following slideshare gives an overview of social machines and SOCIAM:
{{&amp;lt; slideshare id=&amp;ldquo;jogOZAD0VgkoJj&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt;}}
The official website contains detailed information about the numerous aspects, research topics, outputs, and applications of the project.
As a Research Associate, I was involved in a number of different research threads and (sub-)projects within SOCIAM.</description></item><item><title>Integrated Care Pathways for HIV patients</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/hiv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:59:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/hiv/</guid><description>We work in close collaboration with the NHS Lothian and NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde boards to improve HIV care by mapping the processes involved in the form of an Integrated Care Pathways (ICPs). We employ a rigorous methodology involving contextual interviews, questionnaires, and shadowing to capture the and record necessary knowledge. Using the logic-based tool WorkflowFM for this purpose offers the following advantages:
An intuitive, diagrammatic visualisation of the care pathways which helps clinicians better understand their own practices, analyse and rethink them.</description></item><item><title>Lightweight Social Calculus</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/lsc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 20:00:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/lsc/</guid><description>We would like to change the way in which social machines are built. The central premise is: there is a model of interaction which sits behind any social machine, governing who can do what when, which kinds of messages can be sent and to whom, shaping the ways in which the complex socio-technical system unfolds through time. However, these interaction models are often not explicit, transparent, editable, discoverable, composable and so on, as they are scattered through many interacting pieces of code.</description></item><item><title>Sociograms: Rapid assembly of Social Machines</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/sociograms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 16:10:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/sociograms/</guid><description>Our goal is to create a methodology and a tool to design Social Machines using a graphical language (for now dubbed Sociograms) with executable semantics, in the sense that a (basic) working prototype can be automatically generated from a sociagram-based design.
Research questions include:
Can we describe (most) social machines as hypergraphs where nodes are actors and hyperedges are interaction protocols? Can a working prototype be automatically generated from such a structure and if not what additional constraints apply?</description></item><item><title>Healthcare Data Safe Havens</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/farr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 17:51:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/farr/</guid><description>Healthcare Data Safe Havens allow the sharing of healthcare data in a secure infrastructure for extensive, data-intensive experiments being demanded by precision and stratified medicine. A key architectural challenge is how to maintain control of patient data within the governance of local data jurisdictions, while also allowing these jurisdictions to engage with experiment designs that (because of the need to scale to large population sizes) may require analyses across several jurisdictions.</description></item><item><title>Training Platform for Pulmonary Rehabilitation</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/copd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 17:50:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/copd/</guid><description>Image by Patrick J. Lynch, medical illustrator, CC BY 2.5
Description As part of the National Healthcare system, the Edinburgh Community Pulmonary Rehabilitation team is tasked with delivering high quality care, engaging on promoting public health and improving self-management. The Pulmonary Rehabilitation team, based in Leith, has been running since 2008 and receives annually over 650 referrals for Lothian-based individuals living with chronic lung conditions.
The main aim of this project is to develop an interactive, web-based educational platform that can be used as a preparation tool for students attending the Pulmonary Rehabilitation team for their placement.</description></item><item><title>Workflows for burns care in Scotland</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/cobis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 17:51:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/cobis/</guid><description>The Care for Burns in Scotland (COBIS) managed clinical network aims to provide a high standard of care for patients who suffer burn injuries in Scotland. In COBIS, an effort is made to maintain burns data throughout Scotland and develop efficiency and quality indicators for burns care. The difficulty of these tasks is compounded by patient diversity (different patients require different care pathways), the low quality of existing guidelines, the number of different people that can be involved with the same patient, and the occasional digression from standard protocols.</description></item><item><title>Intra-hospital patient transfers</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/patient-transfers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 02:43:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/patient-transfers/</guid><description>We employed our rigorous workflow-based methodology to address safety issues of intra-hospital transfers. Particularly, we devised a framework for systematically generating electronic checklists for healthcare processes, and we applied it to intra-hospital transfers for tracheostomy procedures at St Mary’s Hospital, London. The resulting checklists are guaranteed to reflect the transfer workflows, enforce consistency and completeness, and thus provide enhanced confidence when it comes to patient safety.
Problem Intra-hospital transfers in the UK do not have well-defined guidelines, leading medical staff to employ informal, mostly oral-based means in order to support the transfers.</description></item><item><title>Patterns for collaborative work in healthcare</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/healthcare-collab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 17:51:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/healthcare-collab/</guid><description>We used our rigorous framework to formally verify the correctness of anumber of collaboration patterns in healthcare teams by looking at specifications of responsibility and accountability. Particularly, we analysed two types of patient handovers, which we modelled as process compositions that were then mechanically verified. The formal underpinning of our approach provides guarantees that all the necessary information for the patient handover is communicated, while enforcing the specified conditions for responsibility and accountability in every workflow instance.</description></item><item><title>Data-Driven Management &amp; Digital Consulting Mastercourse</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/posts/celonis-mastercourse-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 11:03:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/posts/celonis-mastercourse-2022/</guid><description>📢 3 Week Mastercourse by Celonis - hosted by AIAI
📅 Online launch: 21 June 2022 2:00pm
PDF Brochure
👉 Register here 👈
The Course Learn together with Germany’s and New York’s most valuable startup Celonis what the Management of tomorrow will look like in a world that is more digitized than ever. Celonis helps organizations track their internal processes based on digital footprints in IT systems. With this Celonis has turned into the market leader for Executive Management Technology with customers like Unilever, Coca Cola or BMW.</description></item><item><title>Postdoctoral Research Position with the ACRC</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/posts/acrc-postdoc-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:16:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/posts/acrc-postdoc-2022/</guid><description>📢 Research Associate in Formal Modelling for Health and Care
📅 Deadline: 24 Jan 2022 10 Jan 2022
📝 Fixed term contract for 30 months
👉 More info and apply here
Come work with Jacques Fleuriot, Jane Hillston and me at the School of Informatics, University of Edinburgh and within the multidisciplinary Advanced Care Research Centre - ACRC (http://edin.care/).
To support meaningful inference and decision making in the context of advanced care delivery for the older person, computer-based models are needed that can capture the vast body of knowledge both around general and specific care pathways and incorporate data from real-time sources such as sensors.</description></item><item><title>Funded PhD opportunity with the ACRC</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/posts/acrc-phd-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/posts/acrc-phd-2022/</guid><description>📢 PhD with Integrated Study in Advanced Care
🎓 Monitoring daily living to predict health outcomes
📅 Deadline: 26 Nov 2021 (rolling)
👉 More info and links
An exciting opportunity for a interdisciplinary PhD in a fully-funded, integrated, 4-year programme at the Advanced Care Research Centre (ACRC) Academy (http://edin.care/academy).
This particular topic involves a combination of IoT and AI, using data-driven and process based techniques to predict health outcomes by monitoring Activities of Daily Living.</description></item></channel></rss>