<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>present on Petros Papapanagiotou</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/categories/present/</link><description>Recent content in present on Petros Papapanagiotou</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© Petros Papapanagiotou</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 23:52:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.petrospap.com/categories/present/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SuprNation</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/suprnation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 23:52:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/suprnation/</guid><description>SuprNation is a technology company founded in 2015 to serve as a home for some of the most competent and creative people in the iGaming industry. Our first product was launched in the summer of 2016, a casino determined to deliver a better user and gaming experience than what is currently available. SuprNation is a highly ambitious project with 3 casino brands, VoodooDreams, NYSpins and Duelz live on the market.</description></item><item><title>Logic-based workflows</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:53:08 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</guid><description>This project aims to enhance the development of process workflows with AI techniques so that various properties of the models are verified as they are being built, i.e. workflows that are correct-by-construction.
In particular, we employ the proofs-as-processes paradigm which describes the correspondence between Classical Linear Logic (CLL) proofs with π-calculus processes. This enables us to create resource-based specifications of processes as logical sequents and compose them via formal proof. The result is a verified workflow with the following properties:</description></item><item><title>Business Process Simulation</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:00:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proter/</guid><description>Proter is an open-source discrete event simulation library for workflows, written in Scala. It is part of our WorkflowFM framework for formal workflow modelling and management and is available on GitHub:
https://github.com/workflowfm/proter
Website and documentation is available here: http://docs.workflowfm.com/proter/
Proter was initially developed for the simulation of logic-based workflows in WorkflowFM in the context of the DigiFlow project. It was then gradually separated into an independent project for general purpose process simulation.</description></item></channel></rss>