<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>project on Petros Papapanagiotou</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/categories/project/</link><description>Recent content in project on Petros Papapanagiotou</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© Petros Papapanagiotou</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 23:10:06 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.petrospap.com/categories/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Logic-based workflows</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:00:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</guid><description>This project aims to enhance the development of process workflows with AI techniques so that various properties of the models are verified as they are being built, i.e. workflows that are correct-by-construction.
In particular, we employ the proofs-as-processes paradigm which describes the correspondence between Classical Linear Logic (CLL) proofs with π-calculus processes. This enables us to create resource-based specifications of processes as logical sequents and compose them via formal proof. The result is a verified workflow with the following properties:</description></item><item><title>Advanced Care Research Centre</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/acrc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 23:10:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/acrc/</guid><description>The Advanced Care Research Centre Programme is a complementary programme of research and development to deliver innovation and change to later life care. It has the following vision:
High‐quality data‐driven, personalised and affordable care that supports the independence, dignity and quality‐of‐life of people in later life living in their own homes and in supported care environments.
It is a large, multidisciplinary programme, involving 6 themes of core work and a doctoral Academy, and funded by Legal &amp;amp; General.</description></item><item><title>Business Process Simulation</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:00:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proter/</guid><description>Proter is an open-source discrete event simulation library for workflows, written in Scala. It is part of our WorkflowFM framework for formal workflow modelling and management and is available on GitHub:
https://github.com/workflowfm/proter
Website and documentation is available here: http://docs.workflowfm.com/proter/
Proter was initially developed for the simulation of logic-based workflows in WorkflowFM in the context of the DigiFlow project. It was then gradually separated into an independent project for general purpose process simulation.</description></item><item><title>DigiFlow</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/digiflow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 17:52:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/digiflow/</guid><description>Digitizing Industrial Workflow, Monitoring and Optimization Digiflow is an Industry 4.0 project funded by EIT Digital. It focuses on the digitization, monitoring, and optimization of industrial workflows, with a combination of IoT sensors, Cloud infrastructure and our workflow technologies.
A slide deck with some of the aspects and outputs of the project for 2018 can be found HERE
We are working on a unique solution to enable manufacturing companies to better monitor their floors and provide decision support towards efficiency optimisation:</description></item><item><title>SOCIAM</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/sociam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:48:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/sociam/</guid><description>SOCIAM was an EPSRC funded project involving the Universities of Oxford, Edinburgh and Southampton, focusing on the theory and practice of social machines.
The following slideshare gives an overview of social machines and SOCIAM:
The official website contains detailed information about the numerous aspects, research topics, outputs, and applications of the project.
As a Research Associate, I was involved in a number of different research threads and (sub-)projects within SOCIAM.</description></item><item><title>Integrated Care Pathways for HIV patients</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/hiv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 16:59:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/hiv/</guid><description>We work in close collaboration with the NHS Lothian and NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde boards to improve HIV care by mapping the processes involved in the form of an Integrated Care Pathways (ICPs). We employ a rigorous methodology involving contextual interviews, questionnaires, and shadowing to capture the and record necessary knowledge. Using the logic-based tool WorkflowFM for this purpose offers the following advantages:
An intuitive, diagrammatic visualisation of the care pathways which helps clinicians better understand their own practices, analyse and rethink them.</description></item><item><title>Lightweight Social Calculus</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/lsc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 16:09:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/lsc/</guid><description>We would like to change the way in which social machines are built. The central premise is: there is a model of interaction which sits behind any social machine, governing who can do what when, which kinds of messages can be sent and to whom, shaping the ways in which the complex socio-technical system unfolds through time. However, these interaction models are often not explicit, transparent, editable, discoverable, composable and so on, as they are scattered through many interacting pieces of code.</description></item><item><title>Sociograms: Rapid assembly of Social Machines</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/sociograms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 16:10:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/sociograms/</guid><description>Our goal is to create a methodology and a tool to design Social Machines using a graphical language (for now dubbed Sociograms) with executable semantics, in the sense that a (basic) working prototype can be automatically generated from a sociagram-based design.
Research questions include:
Can we describe (most) social machines as hypergraphs where nodes are actors and hyperedges are interaction protocols? Can a working prototype be automatically generated from such a structure and if not what additional constraints apply?</description></item><item><title>Healthcare Data Safe Havens</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/farr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 17:51:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/farr/</guid><description>Healthcare Data Safe Havens allow the sharing of healthcare data in a secure infrastructure for extensive, data-intensive experiments being demanded by precision and stratified medicine. A key architectural challenge is how to maintain control of patient data within the governance of local data jurisdictions, while also allowing these jurisdictions to engage with experiment designs that (because of the need to scale to large population sizes) may require analyses across several jurisdictions.</description></item><item><title>Training Platform for Pulmonary Rehabilitation</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/copd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 17:50:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/copd/</guid><description>Image by Patrick J. Lynch, medical illustrator, CC BY 2.5
Description As part of the National Healthcare system, the Edinburgh Community Pulmonary Rehabilitation team is tasked with delivering high quality care, engaging on promoting public health and improving self-management. The Pulmonary Rehabilitation team, based in Leith, has been running since 2008 and receives annually over 650 referrals for Lothian-based individuals living with chronic lung conditions.
The main aim of this project is to develop an interactive, web-based educational platform that can be used as a preparation tool for students attending the Pulmonary Rehabilitation team for their placement.</description></item><item><title>Workflows for burns care in Scotland</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/cobis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 17:51:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/cobis/</guid><description>The Care for Burns in Scotland (COBIS) managed clinical network aims to provide a high standard of care for patients who suffer burn injuries in Scotland. In COBIS, an effort is made to maintain burns data throughout Scotland and develop efficiency and quality indicators for burns care. The difficulty of these tasks is compounded by patient diversity (different patients require different care pathways), the low quality of existing guidelines, the number of different people that can be involved with the same patient, and the occasional digression from standard protocols.</description></item><item><title>Intra-hospital patient transfers</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/patient-transfers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 02:43:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/patient-transfers/</guid><description>We employed our rigorous workflow-based methodology to address safety issues of intra-hospital transfers. Particularly, we devised a framework for systematically generating electronic checklists for healthcare processes, and we applied it to intra-hospital transfers for tracheostomy procedures at St Mary’s Hospital, London. The resulting checklists are guaranteed to reflect the transfer workflows, enforce consistency and completeness, and thus provide enhanced confidence when it comes to patient safety.
Problem Intra-hospital transfers in the UK do not have well-defined guidelines, leading medical staff to employ informal, mostly oral-based means in order to support the transfers.</description></item><item><title>Patterns for collaborative work in healthcare</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/healthcare-collab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 17:51:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/healthcare-collab/</guid><description>We used our rigorous framework to formally verify the correctness of anumber of collaboration patterns in healthcare teams by looking at specifications of responsibility and accountability. Particularly, we analysed two types of patient handovers, which we modelled as process compositions that were then mechanically verified. The formal underpinning of our approach provides guarantees that all the necessary information for the patient handover is communicated, while enforcing the specified conditions for responsibility and accountability in every workflow instance.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:08:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/</guid><description>Current Current research projects I am actively involved in. The list is not exhaustive and excludes new collaborations and proposals under development.
Logic-based workflows 2009-today
Advanced Care Research Centre 2020-today
Business Process Simulation 2019-today
Past These are projects that I have previously been involved in and are now considered to be concluded. Some of these are still being maintained or used in further research.</description></item></channel></rss>