<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>java on Petros Papapanagiotou</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/techs/java/</link><description>Recent content in java on Petros Papapanagiotou</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© Petros Papapanagiotou</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:59:44 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.petrospap.com/techs/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Logic-based workflows</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 23:28:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</guid><description>This project aims to enhance the development of process workflows with AI techniques so that various properties of the models are verified as they are being built, i.e. workflows that are correct-by-construction.
In particular, we employ the proofs-as-processes paradigm which describes the correspondence between Classical Linear Logic (CLL) proofs with π-calculus processes. This enables us to create resource-based specifications of processes as logical sequents and compose them via formal proof. The result is a verified workflow with the following properties:</description></item><item><title>WorkflowFM Composer</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/composer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:32:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/composer/</guid><description>The WorkflowFM Composer is a a diagrammatic tool for formally verified process modelling and composition.
It is available under the Apache 2.0 License on GitHub: https://github.com/workflowfm/workflowfm-composer
Website and documentation is available here: http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/
About The WorkflowFM Composer consists of a Java-based server and GUI for formally verified process composition using the WorkflowFM Reasoner. It provides a visual, diagrammatic interface to specify processes based on their input and output resources, and compose them together to form more complex workflows.</description></item><item><title>Integrated Care Pathways for HIV patients</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/hiv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:59:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/hiv/</guid><description>We work in close collaboration with the NHS Lothian and NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde boards to improve HIV care by mapping the processes involved in the form of an Integrated Care Pathways (ICPs). We employ a rigorous methodology involving contextual interviews, questionnaires, and shadowing to capture the and record necessary knowledge. Using the logic-based tool WorkflowFM for this purpose offers the following advantages:
An intuitive, diagrammatic visualisation of the care pathways which helps clinicians better understand their own practices, analyse and rethink them.</description></item></channel></rss>