<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ocaml on Petros Papapanagiotou</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/techs/ocaml/</link><description>Recent content in ocaml on Petros Papapanagiotou</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© Petros Papapanagiotou</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 20:00:07 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.petrospap.com/techs/ocaml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Logic-based workflows</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 23:28:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/proofs-as-processes/</guid><description>This project aims to enhance the development of process workflows with AI techniques so that various properties of the models are verified as they are being built, i.e. workflows that are correct-by-construction.
In particular, we employ the proofs-as-processes paradigm which describes the correspondence between Classical Linear Logic (CLL) proofs with π-calculus processes. This enables us to create resource-based specifications of processes as logical sequents and compose them via formal proof. The result is a verified workflow with the following properties:</description></item><item><title>WorkflowFM Reasoner</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/reasoner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:32:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/reasoner/</guid><description>The WorkflowFM Reasoner is a logic-based library for correct-by-construction process modelling and composition.
It is available under the Apache 2.0 License on GitHub: https://github.com/workflowfm/workflowfm-reasoner
Website and documentation is available here: http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-reasoner/
About It is implemented as a logic-based library for the interactive theorem prover HOL Light that allows for rigorous, formally verified process specification and composition. The resulting workflows are correct-by-construction with the following verified properties:
Systematic resource accounting: No resources appear out of nowhere or disappear into thin air.</description></item><item><title>HOL Light Embed</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/embedded-logics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:22:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/embedded-logics/</guid><description>I have developed a generic framework to perform object level reasoning with embedded logics in HOL Light. It provides procedural tactics inspired by Isabelle&amp;rsquo;s rule/erule/drule/frule. It also supports correspondences with computational terms in the style of Curry-Howard.
It is available under the BSD-3-Clause License on GitHub: https://github.com/PetrosPapapa/hol-light-embed
Additional information is available in this publication.
A step-by-step tutorial with a detailed example is available here.
What this library does Assuming you have an inductively defined logic encoded in HOL, the library allows you to prove object level theorems within your embedded logic.</description></item><item><title>Isabelle Light</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/isabelle-light/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:22:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/isabelle-light/</guid><description>HOL Light is a modern theorem proving system characterised by its powerful, low level interface that allows for flexibility and programmability. However, considerable effort is required to become accustomed to the system and to reach a point where one can comfortably achieve simple natural deduction proofs.
Isabelle is another powerful and widely used theorem prover that provides useful features for natural deduction proofs, including its meta-logic and its four main natural deduction tactics.</description></item><item><title>Boyer-Moore</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/boyer-moore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:22:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/boyer-moore/</guid><description>In this project, we investigate the potential of the Boyer-Moore waterfall model for the automation of inductive proofs within a modern proof assistant. Based on the concepts and methodology underlying this 40-year-old model, we have implemented a new, fully integrated tool in the theorem prover HOL Light that can be invoked as a tactic.
We have also included several extensions and enhancements to the model. These include the integration of existing HOL Light proof procedures and the addition of state-of-the-art generalization techniques into the waterfall.</description></item><item><title>HOL Light Tools</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/software/hol-light-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 02:22:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/software/hol-light-tools/</guid><description>This is a library of tools, tactics, and theories I have developed in HOL Light.
Some of these, such as the finite map theory, have been ported from the work of others, particularly in HOL4.
Notable things included:
A port of the finite map theory from HOL4. A set of tools to enable proofs in an arbitrarily extended proof state. A small library about substitution. Additional definitions and lemmas for lists, sets, multisets, etc.</description></item><item><title>SOCIAM</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/sociam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:57:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/sociam/</guid><description>SOCIAM was an EPSRC funded project involving the Universities of Oxford, Edinburgh and Southampton, focusing on the theory and practice of social machines.
The following slideshare gives an overview of social machines and SOCIAM:
{{&amp;lt; slideshare id=&amp;ldquo;jogOZAD0VgkoJj&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt;}}
The official website contains detailed information about the numerous aspects, research topics, outputs, and applications of the project.
As a Research Associate, I was involved in a number of different research threads and (sub-)projects within SOCIAM.</description></item><item><title>Integrated Care Pathways for HIV patients</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/hiv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:59:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/hiv/</guid><description>We work in close collaboration with the NHS Lothian and NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde boards to improve HIV care by mapping the processes involved in the form of an Integrated Care Pathways (ICPs). We employ a rigorous methodology involving contextual interviews, questionnaires, and shadowing to capture the and record necessary knowledge. Using the logic-based tool WorkflowFM for this purpose offers the following advantages:
An intuitive, diagrammatic visualisation of the care pathways which helps clinicians better understand their own practices, analyse and rethink them.</description></item><item><title>Lightweight Social Calculus</title><link>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/lsc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 20:00:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.petrospap.com/projects/lsc/</guid><description>We would like to change the way in which social machines are built. The central premise is: there is a model of interaction which sits behind any social machine, governing who can do what when, which kinds of messages can be sent and to whom, shaping the ways in which the complex socio-technical system unfolds through time. However, these interaction models are often not explicit, transparent, editable, discoverable, composable and so on, as they are scattered through many interacting pieces of code.</description></item></channel></rss>